Helen A. C. Long and May Chadwick Collection of Hamilton Manufacturing Graphics 6688 G
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Helen A. C. Long and May Chadwick Collection of Hamilton Manufacturing Graphics
1882-1899
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Helen A. C. Long
May Chadwick
Hamilton Manufacturing
6688 G
2 folders
1 file folder
Plans (Drawings), etchings (prints).
Maps and isometric drawings of Hamilton Manufacturing Company.
10080114
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, November 28, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 28, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The Hamilton Manufacturing Company was a manufacturer of cotton textiles, founded in Lowell, Massachusetts, in 1824.
Scope and Contents
Three sets of four images each. One drawing of the footprints of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company buildings, one map of the buildings and surrounding streets, and two isometric etchings of the buildings.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6688 P: Helen A. C. Long and May Chadwick Collection of Hamilton Manufacturing Photographs
Canals; Centennial Exhibition.; Cotton manufacture; Drawing; Industries; Insurance surveys; Mill agents; Mill superintendents; Overseers; Rivers; Textile factories; Textile industry; Voyages and travels; Waterfalls; Lowell (Mass.); Merrimack Canal (Lowell, Mass.); Merrimack River (N.H. and Mass.); Northern Canal (Lowell, Mass.); Pawtucket Falls (Lowell, Mass.); United States; Amory, Charles B.,; Bartlett, Henry.; Chadwick, Austin.; Chadwick, Julia M. L.; Moulton family.; Moulton, Miranda O.J.; Moulton, Oliver H.; Amoskeag Manufacturing Company; Hamilton Manufacturing Company (Lowell, Mass.); Maine Female Seminary (Gorham, Me.); Merrimack Manufacturing Company; Pemberton Manufacturing Company; Pepperell Manufacturing Company
10080114
- Maps of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company, 1882-1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1882 (drawing?), Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a drawing of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., showing the buildings along the canal. Buildings in background very lightly drawn in. A larger size of this image is reproduced in "City of Lowell, Mass.: Its Commercial and Financial Resources. Souvenir of the Lowell Morning Mail. [Lowell, Mass.]: Wm. Fisk, 1890" (F74.L93L69 1890). Bound with three other items. Copy A. 17.5 x 11.75 cm.
    Format: Etching.
  - Item 2: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map, Map (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy A. 11.25 x 17.5 cm.
    Format: Map.
  - Item 3: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map (isometric view), Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows an isometric view, as if drawn from above, showing the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy A. 17 x 11.5 cm.
  - Item 4: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map, Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy B. 11.25 x 17 cm.
  - Item 4: Plan of Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1899, Map (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a plan of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., dated March 14, 1899, as suggested by O. H. M. (Oliver H. Moulton). Moulton was the superintendent of the Hamilton Mfg. Co. at this time. It is unclear if this was a proposed new building plan. Bound with three other items. Copy A. 17.5 x 11.75 cm.
  - Item 5: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1882 (drawing?), Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a drawing of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., showing the buildings along the canal. Buildings in background very lightly drawn in. A larger size of this image is reproduced in "City of Lowell, Mass.: Its Commercial and Financial Resources. Souvenir of the Lowell Morning Mail. [Lowell, Mass.]: Wm. Fisk, 1890" (F74.L93L69 1890). Bound with three other items. Copy B. 17 x 11.75 cm.
  - Item 6: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map (isometric view), Map (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows an isometric view, as if drawn from above, showing the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy B. 17 x 11.5 cm.
  - Item 8: Plan of Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1899, Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a plan of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., dated March 14, 1899, as suggested by O. H. M. (Oliver H. Moulton). Moulton was the superintendent of the Hamilton Mfg. Co. at this time. It is unclear if this was a proposed new building plan. Bound with three other items. Copy B. 17 x 12 cm.
  - Item 9: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1882 (drawing?), Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a drawing of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., showing the buildings along the canal. Buildings in background very lightly drawn in. A larger size of this image is reproduced in "City of Lowell, Mass.: Its Commercial and Financial Resources. Souvenir of the Lowell Morning Mail. [Lowell, Mass.]: Wm. Fisk, 1890" (F74.L93L69 1890). Bound with three other items. Copy C. 16.5 x 11.25 cm.
  - Item 10: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map, Map (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy C. 11 x 16.75 cm.
  - Item 11: Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1893 insurance map (isometric view), Etching (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts an insurance survey done of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., November 13, 1893. Map shows an isometric view, as if drawn from above, showing the buildings and layout of the company. Bound with three other items. Copy C. 16.5 x 11.5 cm.
  - Item 12: Plan of Hamilton Manufacturing Co., Lowell, Mass., 1899, Map (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [after 1900]. Image depicts a plan of the Hamilton Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., dated March 14, 1899, as suggested by O. H. M. (Oliver H. Moulton). Moulton was the superintendent of the Hamilton Mfg. Co. at this time. It is unclear if this was a proposed new building plan. Bound with three other items. Copy C. 16.75 x 11.5 cm.